He's X rated and animated!
Fritz the Cat is a animation, comedy, drama film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
In late 1960s New York City, fed up with monotonous college life and police repression, free-spirited
Fritz, an impenitent seducer and unrestrained party-animal, decides to explore the world.
And just like that, as he flees NYC, heading to San Francisco,
Fritz embarks on an endless adventure of illumination.
Immersed in a world surrounded by drugs and sex, Fritz participates in mad orgies, brings about a
revolution, incites mass urban riots, and crosses paths with drug-addled Nazi bikers.
Fritz the Cat (voice), played by Skip Hinnant.
Bertha / Additional Female Crows (voice), played by Rosetta LeNoire.
Blue / John / Additional Voices (voice), played by John McCurry.
Pig Cop #2 (voice), played by Phil Seuling.
Winston Schwartz / Lizard Leader (voice), played by Judy Engles.
Narrator / Pig Cop #1 (voice), played by Ralph Bakshi.
Fritz the Cat is a comic strip created by Robert Crumb.
Set in a "supercity" of anthropomorphic animals, it focused on Fritz, a tabby cat who
frequently went on wild adventures that sometimes involved sexual escapades.
Crumb began drawing the character in homemade comic books as a child,
and Fritz would become one of his best-known characters.
The strip first appeared in Help!
and Cavalier magazines, and subsequently in publications associated with the underground comix scene between 1965 and
1972; Fritz the Cat comic compilations elevated it to one of the underground scene's most iconic features.
Fritz the Cat received further attention when it was adapted
into a 1972 animated film of the same name.
The directorial debut of animator Ralph Bakshi, it was the first animated feature film to receive an X
rating in the United States, and the most successful independent animated feature to date.
Crumb ended the strip later that year due to disagreements with the filmmakers.
The film explores themes of new york city, students'
movement, underground, cat, orgy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.